Let's talk about ICICI Lombard. It's
recovered from its opening lows,
reacting to its fourth quarter earnings.
Earlier today, we spoke with the
management on their Q4 performance and
their outlook. But before that, Yash
joins in to give us earnings insights in
our special insight edge segment. Yash.
Well, Manglam, let's look at both
aspects. A, what does the result for the
fourth quarter look like and why the
stock is still under pressure? Though
it's recovered from the lows, but why is
it still under pressure? As far as
results for the fourth quarter are
concerned, they seem strong. The net
earned premium that has grown at 20%
which is a healthy rate at about
5,226 cr. Underwriting loss has reduced
by 11% coming in at about a loss of
about 210 cr rupees. The operating
profit that is down 26% but that is
largely because of the investment income
also uh being being lower to the same
proportion in the fourth quarter. The
combined ratio has been well protected
at 102.5 versus
102.3. Now the PAT is down about 2% in
the quarter. Why the stock is under
pressure? That is because uncertainty on
two things. One is how will the motor
business turn out in uh you know the
coming financial year that is FI26 with
sales seeing some pressure especially
the two-heer sales in the rural pockets
of the country. How will that pan out
for the motor insurance business of ICIC
Lombard? B the entire insurance sector
has been trying for a pricing revision
when it comes to motor third party uh
you know premium prices which are in the
hands of the regulator. No luck so far
for about a few years now. The industry
is hopeful that something will transpire
in FI26 though the management clarifying
to us that there has been no
communication whatsoever, no hint
whatsoever of any pricing revision in
this year as well. so far. So that also
plays as far as the uncertainty point is
concerned. If there is no price
revision, it would adversely impact the
motor portfolio increasing the loss
ratios and that creates a fair bit of
uncertainty and negative uncertainty as
far as that particular stock is
concerned.
All right, Hash, thanks a lot for that.
Let's also hear out what the management
had to say to
us across different segments. I think
the the the road that's kind of laid
down looks very very promising whether
you look at the uh infrastructure
investments that and logistics coming in
on the commercial lines pricing uptick
again happening in that segment health
looking quite promising uh continuing to
uh look to exhibit a double digit growth
and even motor I think in terms of how
do we see things playing out in the
subsequent year uh looks promising so
all in all I think What we would kind of
continue to pencil in is to outperform
the industry in that range of as we keep
saying between 200 to 200 basis points
in so far as topline is concerned and
obviously a trajectory to see an
improvement in
combined. What we've been able to
deliver is a consistent improvement in
combined year on year. uh that's what we
had kind of spoken about as well and uh
even in fact at the beginning of the
year honestly if you look at in our
April 24 earnings call we did kind of
expect the market to be slightly more
semblance in so far as combined ratios
are concerned but if you look at the
9-month numbers the industry has
actually seen an adverse development in
the overall combined in fact it has kind
of moved by about 100 basis points from
112% the previous year 9 months so the
key thing to watch out for is how what
direction does the market take and in
that context is how we will be kind of
positioning our opportunities but
everything remaining the same definitely
we would want to see an improvement in
the combined going ahead and more
importantly as I said the return on
equity range that we want to continue to
start exhibiting to the stakeholders
will be within that 18 to 20%